Dakota L. Ewigman

■ dakota@ewigman.com | 🗖 816-225-6502 | 🕈 Seattle, WA | **in** linkedin.com/in/DakotaEwigman

Summary .

Software Developer with 10 years of experience in software engineering largely working on frontend web development. Have a broad set of skills and experiences ranging from Full stack Web development, automation tools, testing, and browser development. Highly self-motivated and solution-oriented team player with a growth mindset and passion for technical problem solving.

Experience ____

Software Engineer Redmond, WA

MICROSOFT CORPORATION

July 2016 – Present

- Edge Wallet
- Xpay Promo Offers
- Xpay Donation & web apps
- BingAds

Software Engineering Intern

O Fallon, MO

June 2015 - Aug 2015

MASTERCARD INCORPORATED

Automated/versioned setup of development environment

Evaluated and upgraded UX of existing web-app for customers

Freelance App Developer Carmel, IN

ТЕСНИІРНІ

Jan 2015

- Developed Android App to exist with existing web-app
- Defined Specs for web APIs
- Self-taught a lot of common practices/skills while on the job

Software Engineering Intern

Kansas City, MO

CERNER CORPORATION May 2013 – Aug 2014

- Developed and ran 20 1 week long app development summer camps for K-8th grade children
- Developed and maintained website for information, registration and payment for the camps
- Developed tools to use for learning and collaboration
- · Created an app for tracking and monitoring servers mantenence

Education

BS in Computer Science, BS in Computer Engineering

GPA: 3.47/4.00

MISSOURI UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY

Aug 2012 - May 2016

Student Council Webmaster & Student IT Chair, Delta Sigma Phi Webmaster & Treasurer

Skills

Programming JS/Typescript, C#, C++, T-SQL Design HTML, CSS, Markdown, LATEX

Frameworks React, Redux, Knockout, web components

Software Tools Git, Powershell, Bash

Miscellaneous MS Office, Android, Windows, Linux, Azure DevOps, GitHub

Awards

2021

Greatness Award - Customer Obsessed, BingAds Engineering